[Music]
hello everyone
so in this video i'd like to share with
you a routine of self-care
i have a video i made on instagram that
goes into detail on what i use
and how i resolve my skin issues so if
that is what you're interested in
you can check those out today i'll give
you a general idea of what i do
in the evenings and mornings as well as
making my own year's supply of hand soap
that i keep by my sink
while i love making my own skin products
much of it is only used on my hands and
feet
since they're not very sensitive i also
make my own oils for massage
but when it comes to my face and neck
and the majority of my body
i have incredibly sensitive skin and
really need to follow the regimen
prescribed by
a dermatologist
when it comes to taking care of my mind
and body i've not always had a routine
i would prioritize other things over it
i
tend to be far more anxious in the past
and self-conscious
of the blemishes that i had on my face
and back for many years
throughout my teens in adulthood i
recently realized that between ages 14
and 18 you can't really find that many
photos of me because i avoided it
and in retrospect i wish i had photos at
that time in my life it makes me a
little
sad the irony of all this is that i
dislike the state of my skin but
really didn't take the time to learn how
to properly care for it
and develop the patients needed to
really resolve issues
there is no instant gratification when
it comes to health and healing of the
mind body and soul
you really need to work at it in my
experience and to do proper self-care
you really need to implement a healthy
lifestyle change
[Music]
for me the first change that made the
biggest difference on both my skin and
well-being
was drastically lowering the amount of
sugar in my diet
i'm someone who loves sweets and
convenience food especially sweet drinks
so that was really hard to do the only
way i was able to do it was by replacing
all the ice cream and goodies with fruit
and drinks with sparkling water
over time i really did start getting a
taste for whole foods and fruits and
vegetables
and that can be tricky because those
foods are expensive
i always like being budget conscious so
i really like to be aware of what is on
sale and buy in bulk when i can
i also try to stay active and of course
exercise nearly every day
[Music]
the other thing i realized was vital to
my health was finding healthy outlets
for stress
and managing it overall a large
component of stress is mental and really
training yourself to think positively
and calm your own mind
is crucial to long-term health
lastly i've found possibly the most
powerful part of self-care
is to be truly comfortable in your own
skin and accepting
yourself as you are and i will share
with you some rather unusual ways i
became confident with my appearance
i think that the majority of what we are
self-conscious about is instigated by
external experiences
feedback and social media for example
if you are surrounded with images and
videos that focus on appearance and
attractiveness
then it makes sense that it's on your
mind much more and it has greater value
one way i gained confidence was simply
investing time and money into hobbies
and things completely unrelated to my
body
i minimized the amount of media i
consumed related on appearances
i realized how so much of what we are
exposed to
is actually just advertisements that
want you to spend money on things that
are
unlikely to lead to long-term happiness
and satisfaction
[Music]
another way i began to love my features
even ones that didn't necessarily adhere
to the current beauty trend
was by really delving into my ancestry
and learning about my origin story
i'm multiracial and come from ancestors
that originated in very different parts
of the world
my people enriched their cultures with
their personal stories
they suffered and laughed and told
stories the experiences of their lives
reflected in the lines and shapes of
their faces and bodies
i represent a melding of their features
by wishing to change
a part of my body i may be erasing a
marker of where i came from
the story of my ancestry for example
i was so insecure about my nose when i
was younger i also sometimes wanted
straight hair
because all my friends had it but now
i've really embraced both these things
as representative of my mixed race
and i truly believe that by changing
these things i take away what is so
unique about my appearance
and this goes for everyone when you're
multiracial you sometimes feel
unsure of where you belong as you may
not feel like your appearance reflects
the very group of people that make up
part of your ancestry
and yet even within that i found a lot
of confidence by realizing that
i reflect the love my parents shared one
so strong that they were willing to deal
with the challenges of being a
multi-racial couple
in order to be together and have a
family it wasn't always easy for them
and i'm so proud that i'm part of their
story
[Music]
i deeply encourage you to connect with
your past and discover the stories of
your people
wherever they come from in every human
narrative there's tragedy and resilience
and rich storytelling
embrace it and you are embracing the
origin of the body you inherited
by learning new things and skill sets i
was constantly reminding myself
that my appearance is the least
interesting thing about who i
am and that doesn't mean not caring
about how you look
just putting a healthy amount of value
in it over time as i grew older
how i looked became a nice compliment to
my identity
but not a focus anymore i rarely feel
insecure about my appearance anymore
because i know
i'm content with myself and being alone
with my thoughts
and the body that holds me is one that
has gotten me through so much in my life
and now i find the most attractive body
to be simply a healthy one
[Music]
as you can see my self-care routine in
regards to products i use
is quite simple i don't really want to
spend potential book buying money on
skin and hair care
so i really keep it minimal while
prioritizing health
i do not care about anti-aging i
honestly think it's a little silly
because i have always found older people
to be so beautiful and interesting
i look forward to getting older and
embracing a beauty that shows that i've
lived a full life
and spent time outdoors i just really
care about my health
for example i use sunscreen every day
and a hat
and sunglasses and even wear a light
coat if i'm going to be outdoors for a
long time
that's the most important part of my
skincare routine
as for my hair i hope it's not too
disappointing to say that i literally
just spray it with water every morning
to define the curls
i think it's very easy to be convinced
by online ads that you need a lot more
products than you really do
there's so much out there to buy and
while it's wonderful to indulge yourself
and i definitely like to feel pampered
occasionally
on a daily basis i really just value my
sun's green and moisturizer
and water if i'm looking for that
pampered feeling without wanting to
spend a lot on products
and be wasteful i usually take a cool
washcloth and lay it over my eyes
while listening to some very relaxing
music i really like the sound of singing
bowls
giving myself a scalp massage with my
fingers
sometimes i take a good old drugstore
moisturizer and
spend some meditative minutes giving
myself a leg or arm massage
i'll light some candles get some tea and
listen to an audiobook
i truly think a calm atmosphere is all
you need to really train your mind to
quiet town
again i hope this video was interesting
or helpful
and that if you're interested in getting
more details i encourage you to check
out the instagram video i made
linked below i hope you all have a
lovely day
or night
[Music]
you